¡÷/savechat  :  sauvegarder le contenu de la fenêtre de chat
#
¡÷Maintenir la touche Ctrl puis * pour changer l'oppacité de la mini-carte 
#
¡÷Maintenir la touche Shift puis utiliser le Clic Droit de la souris pour ajuster l'angle de vue. Pour revenir à l'angle de vue d'origine, presser la touche Shift puis faire un double Clic Droit avec la souris 
#
¡÷Hold the ctrl key and drag with the right mouse button to zoom in and out. To restore the original zoom, hold the ctrl key and double click the right mouse button. The mouse wheel can also be used to zoom in and out
#
¡÷When you move the mouse cursor over monsters, it will change to a sword and you can then attack
#
¡÷Experience gained from killing a monster is proportional to the damage done to the monster. *When more than one player attack the same monster, the first player to attack will get more experience
#
¡÷Hold the ctrl key and attack a monster to lock-on attack status which will automatically attack the target untill the monster is killed. To cancel automatic attack, just click anywhere else
#
¡÷[Left click] on a item on the ground to pick it up. Items that you picked up will show in the inventory
#
¡÷[Right click] on an item to see a description of the item
#
¡÷The two bars below your feet are the HP and SP. The green is the HP and the blue is the SP. The player dies when HP drops to 0. To act as a warning, the HP bar will turn to red when player's HP is at or below 25%
#
¡÷When the EXP bar is full (100%), base level will rise, and player is awarded with Status Points to invest freely in the desired attributes
#
¡÷When the JOBEXP bar below the EXP bar is full (100%), job level will rise, and player is awarded with skill point to invest freely in the desired skill
#
¡÷HP and SP recovers slowly when players stand still. *The recoversy speed doubles when players are sitting. However, when the player carries more than 50% on weight, then HP and SP cannot be recovered automatically
#
¡÷Weight : displayed as carried weight and maximum loading weight. Players cannot carry the items more than maximum loading weight. Carried weight will turn red if it exceeds half of the maximum loading weight, and HP and SP auto recovery will stop. When carried weight exceeds 90% of maximum loading weight, the player will not be able to attack or use skills
#
¡÷Zeny : this is the currency used in Ragnarok Online. *It is automatically deducted when players trade or make purchases
#
¡÷When base level rises, players are awarded with Status Points which can be invested in their attributes
#
¡÷STR (strength) : directly affects the player's attack. The higher the strength the more items one can carry. Increasing strength increases attack
#
¡÷DEX (dexterity) : directly affects the use of weapons. The higher the dexterity, the more efficient that weapons will become. When using bow and arrow, increasing DEX increases attack and accuracy; it also influences spell cast speed
#
¡÷AGI (agility) : directly related to the player's agility. Increasing agility increases possibility of dodging enemy attacks; and the attack speed of various weapons will also rise
#
¡÷VIT (vitality) : directly related to the player's defence and HP. Higher VIT increases defence and decreses damage taken when attacked; it also increases maximum HP and HP recovery rate
#
¡÷INT (intelligence) : directly related to the player's SP. Higher INT increases magic attack (MATK) and magic defence (MDEF)
#
¡÷LUK (luck) : luck is direcly related to various things, increasing LUK affects mainly the probability of critical hits and lucky (dodging enemy attacks purely by luck)
#
¡÷[Print Screen] or [Scroll Lock] : take a screenshot. Screenshots will be saved in the [ScreenShot] files
#
¡÷[F10] : adjust the size of the chat window
#
¡÷[F11] : keep only the basic information window and chat window; closes all other windows
#
¡÷[F12] : open/close the hot key bar. *Drag frequently used items or skills onto the F1-F9 keys, then press the corresponding key for quick access
#
¡÷[INSERT] : sit or stand *Equivalent to entering [/sit] or [/stand] in the chat window. HP and SP recovery is twice as fast sitting than standing
#
¡÷[Alt] + [End] : toggle the [HP/SP] bars beneath the character on/off
#
¡÷[Alt] + [Home] : toggle indication of accessible areas on the minimap on/off
#
¡÷[Alt] + [=] : toggle input status between double-byte and single-byte input. Commands entered in double-byte characters will not be executed; only single-byte commands will be executed
#
¡÷[Alt] + [F10] : toggle chat window on/off
#
[Alt] + [1~9] , [Ctrl] + [-,=,w] :[Alt] + [1~9] uses the following emotions: exclamation, question mark, music, heart, sweat, light bulb, anger, cloud, money, eclipse. [Ctrl] + [-,=,w] : scissors, stone and paper 

¡÷/WHO : display the number of players online of the server
#
¡÷/WHERE : display information and coordinate of player's current location
#
¡÷/H : display descriptions of basic commands
#
¡÷/BGM : toggle background music on/off. *Can also be done in the windows by pressing [Alt] + [0]
#
¡÷/SOUND : toggle sound effects on/off. *Can also be done in the windows by pressing [Alt] + [0]
#
¡÷/EFFECT : toggle various graphical effects in the game on/off. *The game will run smoother when turn the effects off
#
¡÷/SKIP : toggle screen synchronization on/off
#
¡÷/EX [character name] : ignore all 1:1 chat coming from the said player
¡÷/IN [character name] : accept 1:1 chat coming from the said player
#
¡÷/EXALL : ignore all conversation coming from any player
¡÷/INALL : accept conversation coming from any player
#
¡÷/EX : display a list of players being ignored
#
¡÷/ORGANIZE [party name] : to form a party. *Captains of parties may invite other players to join
#
¡÷Right click on the player you want to invite and choose the "Invite into party" to invite the player to join
#
¡÷/LEAVE : leave your current party. *There will be no additional confirmation if you use this command
#
¡÷/EXPEL [character name] : the party captain may expel a specific member from the party. *There will be no additional confirmation if you use this command
#
¡÷Click the [circle] on the bottom right corner of the chat window and choose "party channel" to use the party channel and chat with party members
#
¡÷%  : add % at the beginning of a message to chat in the party channel directly; or hold the ctrl key and then press enter to send the message directly to party members  
#
¡÷the minimap on the top right-hand corner will show the position of all the party members
#
¡÷1:1 Chat : input character name on the left of the chat window and the message on the right; toggle between the two fields quickly by using the TAB key
#
¡÷the minimap keys [+/-] will zoom in/out on the map 
#
¡÷[MVP system] : when fighting Boss level monsters, to protect the rights of the player dealing the most damage, the Boss's MVP item will be dropped automatically in the MVP player's inventory; if the Boss monster did not drop MVP items, then the player is compensated with 50% of the experience
#
¡÷The game window can be moved when playing in windowed mode. Hold [Alt] + [Space] and press the [m] key, then use the direction arrows or the mouse to move the game window
#
¡÷/fog : toggle fog effect on/off. Fog effects better represent the weather of various maps. For players with lower-end computers, this increases the computing load. If the game halts or exits abnormally, we recommend players to turn off fog effect. Fog can be turned on/off permanently in Config
#
¡÷Items found on monsters are unidentified; use magnifying glasses bought from tool shops to identify and verify the effects and usage of items
#
¡÷If Hunters want to use the Trap series of skills, they must have the¡mBooby Trap¡nitem on them
#
¡÷One Emperium is required to make a guild (union); the command is /GUILD [guild name] , the name cannot contain special characters or spaces. Alt + G opens the guild window
#
¡÷Guild members may use /GC [message] or $ [message] or press Alt + Enter for guild chat
#
¡÷To insert a card to a slot on the equipment, first un-equip the item, then double click on the card. A list of items available for the card will appear for selection
#
¡÷Description of courtesy point system   
--Novices may use this starting from Basic Skills level 8
--Right click on a player and choose to give courtesy point
#
¡÷Description of some abnormal status
--Stun : when stunned, players will not be able to move
--Darkness : screen turns dark; for monsters, this means a shorter radius of vision
--Frozen : unable to move; recovers only when attacked
#
¡÷Experience values will be deducted at death. After using skills or a battle, a 5-second delay is forced before you may go offline
#
¡÷Query the Kapra staff for access to storage, save points and leasing pushcarts.
#
¡÷[Alt] + [J] : Can use to see the adopt pet's
#
¡÷Function follow people : Click the key [Shift] + [right click]
#
¡÷[Alt] + [L] : Use for emotion bar, click  Alt+M or Alt+L to choose your prefer emotion.
#